It takes place here, in the brain, it takes place here,
in the digestive tract, but now we're going to add after the rotation, like this,
for my limbs, okay, the same
applies to my lower limbs, it happens at the same time, here,
it happens at the same time there, it happens at the same time there.
A tendinitis can be the expression of a rotation deficit.
of your peritoneum, you see.
For example, someone who has a problem with their arm here,
I don't know, they have a problem
in the tendon area, or etc.
And we say, it’s a tendinitis in the wrist.
Someone tells me, hey, that's strange,
I've never played tennis,
I went to the doctor, he told me I had tennis elbow.
I've never done that.
However,
very often, we need to see what's happening
on the pulmonary level or viscerally.
And in fact, we need to think
about the organizational phase.
of the system, so you will just understand look at what's happening here
and there
and when you start to understand where this connects here you start where to treat the visceral so
to re-establish visceral spirals to free the limbs and vice-versa to free
sometimes peripheral
problems, that's what in Chinese medicine we do, we will needle very
specific points in your periphery, the imprint is always present
The peritoneum can regress in time if necessary to reuse
a function that was present at some point.
All our major life wounds happen before the age of 5.
Abandonment, rejection, injustice, some things even happen in the embryonic phase.
But what I mean is that what happens here can express itself in the reflections that happen here.
I need this coelom here and my neural tube.
There is an angle here.
This is where there will be a suction field, it's a bit more specific level.
I have here a metabolic field with
a restriction field and there an overgrowth field.
This will immediately create a movement, a little palette here, as if it's not growing
it does this.
It's through this angle here, and in fact it's related to the angle with my coelom and my
neural tube which is behind.
I have an angulation with my neural tube and my coelom,
that there's a restriction field.
From the cardinal vein, I have a vein that will push.
I will have a larger nourishment field and a brake.
And here I have an acceleration and there I have less.
And through this way, it will grow, and here it grows more slowly.
And the fact that I have this differential growth speed given by the vascular system
will actually bring about a field of...
activation.
This means we say, this phrase,
the very active metabolism will cause a powerful flow in the mesenchymal tissue,
which will lead to growth in the canalization system
and will improve the mesenchymal metabolism.
This induction will provoke a growth followed by the ectodermal tissue.
So it's primarily my mesodermal plan that will be induced.
This is linked to this vascular field.
The hand does not appear last, it appears first.
So first,
and then it's the system that elongates. We will take this hand as the
descent point
I reverse my reference point; the first major articulation was the flexion
of my embryo, okay
this flexion of my embryo is the growth speed in relation to my aorta and
so
what do I do? I flex, but if you look all the joints follow the
same protocol. Why does it go inward? Because I have my artery from
my cardinal vein that will give a branch in a trophic flow here
which will be the primitive of my brachiocephalic system.
I will do this and I will come towards here.
Here, it grows faster.
So I do this forward.
If I flex like this, I will flex here
because here, I have a vessel, there, I don't.
Since I don't have one, it will densify, it will create the ridges.
But it’s not because I have the ridges that I didn’t go that way.
It's because...
I had no vessel. The pattern is I'm wrapping around
my vascular system.
So it's a movement first of external rotation
followed by an internal counter-rotation
from my vascular field of internal counter-rotation. One,
two. And the opposite for my limbs.
It's my somite, little by little, here, with the vascular field, that will lift the epiblast.
There's no pattern that’s shown here, but that's what's going to give,
because don’t forget I will have the myotome, etc.
It's the mesoblast that will give the induction.
So that's really the meso that will push.
So my limbs are an expansion of the cardio-pleuro-peritoneal sac.
Everything that is tendons, everything that is vessels, will come from the lateral mesoblast.
The treatment of a limb injury involves their rebalancing
with the pleuro-pericardio-peritoneal system.
To treat a limb is to reintegrate it into the abdominothoracic cavity.
You will clear the entire peritoneal system by freeing the limbs.
The mesenteric axis, you put yourself on the system and you release the entire peritoneum in its phase
of rotation.
On the axis.
Here, you have more emergence here for the upper limb, more
emergence here for the lower limbs.
I take the hand because it's the emergence.
It's like I'm pulling on the zipper and I position myself on the posterior axis here.
It creates a movement like this first and then it does this at the end.
I position myself on the vascular axis from the heel to the endothelium.
The endothelium.
it's the peritoneum of the vessels.
Here, we see he explains the median axis, all the metamers.
You see this external rotation of my limbs.
And then at some point, the shoulder does this movement well, then it does this.
The same goes for the limbs.
Initially, it’s positioned like this.
And then through this beating movement, you will find another arrangement of
your segmentation.
If I return it to the movement, I will just find a very simple mapping.
That seemed...
Here, I mean in S1 or S2, will be found with these other lines
that will define themselves
with respect to these lines, the whole neural metameric layout that will redistribute
through these patterns.
Don’t forget that each metamer, one organized by my vessel, two,
this neural crest
that comes around, which gives this organization, each vertebra corresponds ultimately
to about
one organ or something like that.
But I prefer the idea of Jarricot, multiple dermal vertebrae, one organ dermal.
So you have the angle of hearing. Just below, you see, you have a dermal region at the
level of D8 that corresponds to the liver. Just below, you have another, a little lower here,
that will
correspond to the pyloric center. Then you have the gallbladder and there you
have the pancreas.
For me, it's this line that greatly interested me with the kidneys being taken here. When I take,
I know where I am.
I have the rib, at the same time the parietal pleura
with counter-rotation at the level of my visceral pleura.
At the level of my extremities, there is an induction of the coelom.
The induction of the coelom is the orientation by the vascular field.
We can clearly see the small palette of the hand, the growth here, increasing more and more.
We can see clearly that it ends towards the heart.
with the centrifugal centripetal information given by
the heartbeat in reverse movement at the
level of the lower limbs, it's an internal rotation
with a counter-rotation like the other
like here it makes a movement like that, don’t forget this movement
and it’s the opposite
at the level of my limbs. A movement and finally it will be like this
But it starts first with the opening here.
And it follows my vascular field.
In the growth here of the embryo, it's the bone that is active and c
it's the muscle that is passive.
It's a play between the stretching of the dilation field and
the growth of the bone.
That's why if we go on its fulcrum, we will search for the bone in the fluid,
since initially, it's fluid.
When you see an ilium, it is formed.
Of three parts, the ilium, the ischium, and the pubis.
The shape of the bone, at some point, will be linked to this dilation field.
The
bone is the motor, and you see at first, when you see the little bones of a baby,
the bone, the motor is there and then it changes.
It's the muscle that takes its activity.
And that's when the shape begins to define itself with precision.
I will pull on a...
This is the great spiral of the development of my limbs, my upper and lower limbs,
and the organization of my peritoneum.
This is the counter-rotation.
The embryonic movement is a movement like this.
It's the opposite. This is the counter-rotation.
The base of the skull derives from para-axial mesenchyme.
The face, the jaws, the teeth derive from the crest.
neural. The spinal column and the ribs derive from paraxial mesenchyme.
The skeleton
of the limbs derives from the somatopleure, which will form the limb buds. What
we retain is that treating the face, the teeth, involves balancing them
with their original rhombomere. The base of the skull, the spine, is treated in a
homologous way, similarly,
while all limb injuries involve treating them with the pleuro-pericardio-peritoneum. Treating a limb is
to reintegrate them into their peritoneal cavity. This is a key regarding the
embryonic fulcrum.